A Guide to the Gladys Davis Turner Collection, 1889-1986
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
The Edgar Cayce Foundation
Gladys Davis Turner Collection, 1889-1986
The Edgar Cayce Foundation, Virginia Beach, Virginia
Coll. 8
11.8 Linear Feet
Turner, Gladys Davis; Turner, Albert E.; Wilmore, Leslie Seward; Davis, Mildred
Arrangement
Arranged in 6 series: 1. Binders, 1889-1986. 2. Date books, 1900-1986. 3. Observation notebooks, 1932-1935. 4. Artifacts, 1948-1975. 5. Files, 1929-1986. 6. Books and oversize, 1909-1983.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes both professional and personal papers of Gladys Davis Turner, Edgar Cayce's long-time stenographer and secretary and co-founder of the Edgar Cayce Foundation in Virginia Beach, Virginia.
- Binders, 1889-1986
  - Box 1
    - binder [294 dream readings], 1958; Folder 1:1
    - binder [Albert Turner Memory Book], 1889-1970; Folder 1:2-1:4
  - Box 2
    - addendum [Albert Turner Memory Book], 1951-1972; Folder 2:1
    - binder [Albert Turner Memory Book], 1971-1981; Folder 2:2
    - binder [A.R.E. Activities], 1935-1951; Folder 2:3
    - binder [A.R.E. Library Conference Center Community Dedication], 1975; Folder 2:4
    - binder [A.R.E. Publishing Committee], 1981-1984; Folder 2:5
  - Box 3
    - binder [A.R.E. Study Group Manual], 1936-1962; Folder 3:1
    - binder [Aura Chart Readings by Edgar Cayce], 1941-1943; Folder 3:2
    - binder [Cayce formulas], undated; Folder 3:3
    - binder [board policy excerpts: A.R.E., E.C.F., A.U. for E.C.F. office, extracted by GDT], 1983; Folder 3:4
    - binder [cards], 1985-1986; Folder 3:5
    - binder [Cayce products correspondence], 1978; Folder 3:6
  - Box 4
    - binder [Congress Course: The Mind of Man], 1961; Folder 4:1-4:2
    - binder [Congress workbook], 1980; Folder 4:3-4:4
    - binder [date sequence letters], 1929-1977; Folder 4:5-4:6
  - Box 5
    - binder [diary with publication supplements], 1950-1963; Folder 5:1
    - binder [Edgar Cayce letters loaned to Noel Langley, 8/12/1966], 1930-1945; Folder 5:2
    - binder [Edgar Cayce Readings according to type, date], 1982; Folder 5:3
    - binder [Edgar Cayce Readings alphabetical listing], undated; Folder 5:4-5:5
  - Box 6
    - binder [Edgar Cayce Readings chronological listing], 1906-1944; Folder 6:1-6:4
    - binder [Edgar Cayce Readings numerical changes], 1969; Folder 6:5
    - binder [Edgar Cayce Readings Report File: Cures], 1932-1960; Folder 6:6
  - Box 7
    - binder [extracts from the EC Readings on China, Gobi, Indo-China and Mongolia], undated; Folder 7:1
    - binder [Glad Helpers readings, 281-1 - 281-40], 1931-1939; Folder 7:2
    - binder [Gladys' 60th Anniversary], 1983-1984; Folder 7:3-7:4
  - Box 8
    - binder [Gladys' Memory Book], 1983-1985; Folder 8:1
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1901-1922; Folder 8:2
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1923-1924; Folder 8:3
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1925; Folder 8:4
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1926; Folder 8:5
  - Box 9
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1927; Folder 9:1
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1928; Folder 9:2
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1929; Folder 9:3
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1930; Folder 9:4
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1931; Folder 9:5
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1932; Folder 9:6
  - Box 10
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1933; Folder 10:1
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1934-1939; Folder 10:2
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1940-1949; Folder 10:3
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E., 1950-1969; Folder 10:4
  - Box 11
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1970-1971; Folder 11:1
    - binder [Historical Events of the A.R.E.], 1980-1983; Folder 11:2
    - binder [Incarnations Index: All Periods by Case Numbers], 1957-1978; Folder 11:3
    - binder [Instructions for Journal Indexing; Source File; Reports], undated; Folder 11:4
    - binder [June Congress 1961; GDT's Mind of Man class], Folder 11:5
  - Box 12
    - binder [Les Says Book 1], 1972-1982; Folder 12:1
    - binder [Les Says Book 2], 1982-1985; Folder 12:2
    - binder [manuscript: Old Places in the New World], undated; Folder 12:3-12:4
    - binder [My Years With Edgar Cayce], 1971-1976; Folder 12:5
  - Box 13
    - binder [Outline for 60 Minute Documentary Film on Edgar Cayce], 1965-1970; Folder 13:1
    - binder [Physician's Reference Notebook], 1968; Folder 13:2-13:3
    - binder [Physician's Reference Notebook: Chiropractic Edition Section II], 1972; Folder 13:4
    - binder [A Psychic's Religious Experiences: Gladys Davis' class at June Congress], 1936-1950; Folder 13:5
    - binder [public speaking and publications of Gladys Davis Turner], 1945-1967; Folder 13:6
  - Box 14
    - binder [Readings Survey], 1972; Folder 14:1
    - binder [Selections from the Readings] A-J, 1940-1960; Folder 14:2
    - binder [Selections from the Readings] K-Z, 1940-1970; Folder 14:3
    - binder [Weekly Readings Extracts], 1944-1953; Folder 14:4
    - binder [Work Readings], 1911-1926; Folder 14:5
  - Box 15
    - binder [Work Readings], 1926-1928; Folder 15:1
    - binder [Work Readings], 1928-1931; Folder 15:2
    - binder [Work Readings], 1931-1936; Folder 15:3-15:4
    - binder [Work Readings], 1936-1944; Folder 15:5
- Date Books, 1900-1986
  - Box 16
    - appointment books, 1980-1986; Folder 16:1
  - Box 17
    - date books, 1900-1933; Folder 17:1
  - Box 18
    - date books, 1934-1944; Folder 18:1
- Observation Notebooks, 1932-1935
  - Box 19
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1932-1933; Folder 19:1
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1932-1934; Folder 19:2
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:3
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:4
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:5
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:6
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:7
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:8
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:9
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934; Folder 19:10
    - notebook [Notes and Observations on Edgar Cayce During Readings], 1934-1935; Folder 19:11
- Artifacts, 1948-1975
  - Box 20
    - embroidery [likeness of Greta Garbo], 1975; Folder 20:1
    - ephemera, undated; Folder 20:2
    - framed dogwood flower, 1974; Folder 20:3
    - funeral register, 1968; Folder 20:4
    - plaque [dedication of Edgar Cayce's office at Arctic Crescent], 1948; Folder 20:5
    - plaque [Moon landing commemoration], 1969; Folder 20:6
- Files, 1929-1986
  - Box 21
    - address book, 1978; Folder 21:1
    - cook book [Better Homes and Gardens De Luxe Edition], 1942; Folder 21:2-21:3
    - extracts from Edgar Cayce Readings [nutrition and health], 1930-1944; Folder 21:4
    - personal recipes, 1968-1978; Folder 21:5
    - correspondence [personal], 1968-1986; Folder 21:6-21:7
    - correspondence [professional], 1972-1986; Folder 21:8-21:9
  - Box 22
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] archival notes, undated; Folder 22:1
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] What is Truth?; The Holy Ghost; What Is My Soul, and What Am I Intended to Do With It?], 1929; Folder 22:2
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Man's Relationship to God, 1929; Folder 22:3
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] The Inter-Conscious Mind], 1931; Folder 22:4
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Astrology, 1930; Folder 22:5
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Dreams, 1931; Folder 22:6
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] The Subconscious Mind, 1930; Folder 22:7
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Mind as Related to Healing, 1931; Folder 22:8
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Mind Reading and Telepathy, 1931; Folder 22:9
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Fate, 1931; Folder 22:10
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Faith, 1931; Folder 22:11
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Numerology, 1931; Folder 22:12
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Vibration, 1931; Folder 22:13
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Psychic Phenomena], 1931; Folder 22:14
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] The Aura, 1931; Folder 22:15
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Relativity of Force, 1931; Folder 22:16
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Personality and Individuality, 1931; Folder 22:17
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Hypnotism, 1931; Folder 22:18
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Psycho-Analysis, 1931; Folder 22:19
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Reincarnation, 1931; Folder 22:20
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Evolution, 1931; Folder 22:21
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] The First Ten Minutes After Death, 1931; Folder 22:22
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] What Is Spirituality, 1931; Folder 22:23
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] Where is Heaven?, 1931; Folder 22:24
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] Present World Conditions; How to Develop Your Psychic Powers, 1932; Folder 22:25
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] How to Develop Your Psychic Powers; The Second Coming; Continuity of Life: A Compilation, 1932-1934; Folder 22:26
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] What Is A Reading?, 1933; Folder 22:27
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] The Visible and the Invisible, 1933; Folder 22:28
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] First the Individual; Continuity of Life; The Second Coming, 1933-1934; Folder 22:29
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] Practical Application of Psychic Phenomena; What is Soul Power?; My Work with the Association, 1934-1935; Folder 22:30
    - lectures [Edgar Cayce] The Association for Research and Enlightenment; I Can't Explain it but...; Bible Interpretations, 1936-1938; Folder 22:31
    - lecture [Edgar Cayce] What I Believe, 1944; Folder 22:32
    - newsclipping [Cayce Hospital Closed], 1931; Folder 22:33
  - Box 23
    - greeting and memorial cards [Albert Turner], 1968-1969; Folder 23:1
    - greeting cards, 1979-1985; Folder 23:2-23:4
  - Box 24
    - greeting cards, 1976-1986; Folder 24:1-24:7
  - Box 25
    - notes, undated; Folder 25:1
    - pamphlets, 1947-1983; Folder 25:2
    - photographs [Albert Turner and Gladys Davis Turner], 1964-1967; Folder 25:3
    - photographs [A.R.E. people], 1947-1979; Folder 25:4
    - photographs [Cayce family, 1941-1943; Folder 25:5
    - portrait [Albert Turner], 1968; Folder 25:6
    - postcards, 1940-1980; Folder 25:7
    - publications [A.R.E.], 1971-1983; Folder 25:8
    - publications [written by Gladys Davis Turner], 1923-1959; Folder 25:9
    - tarot cards, undated; Folder 25:10
    - Les Wilmore, A.R.E. Egypt / Israel Tour material, 1976; Folder 25:11
  - Box 25A, Turner, Albert E.; Albert Turner's correspondence and research materials from his work as a member of the Virginia Committee to Abolish Capital Punishment.
    - articles, 1953-1962; Folder 25A:1
    - church publications on capital punishment, 1959-1961; Folder 25A:2
    - correspondence [Cecil Evans] Quaker Program at the United Nations, 1959-1962; Folder 25A:3
    - correspondence [Edgar Labat], 1961-1965; Folder 25A:4
    - correspondence [United States Department of State], 1960; Folder 25A:5
    - correspondence [Virginia Committee to Abolish Capital Punishment], 1959-1962; Folder 25A:6
    - correspondence [Louise Wilson], 1961-1964; Folder 25A:7
    - journal [Friends Journal] Friends Publishing Corporation, 1961; Folder 25A:8
    - journal [The Southern Friend: A Religious and Literary Journal] Woodland, North Carolina, 1956-1957; Folder 25A:9
    - magazine [Adult Student] General Board of Education of the Methodist Church, 1957; Folder 25A:10
    - magazine [Liberation] The Libertarian Press, 1960; Folder 25A:11
    - magazine [The Presidio] Iowa State Penitentiary, 1959-1962; Folder 25A:12
    - minutes [Committee on Citizen Participation Session on Capital Punishment] The American Correctional Association, 1959; Folder 25A:13
    - minutes [Virginia Beach Monthly Meeting of the Religious Society of Friends], 1967; Folder 25A:14
    - newsclippings [capital punishment], 1955-1961; Folder 25A:15
    - newsletter [Legislative Report: Massachusetts Council for the Abolition of the Death Penalty], 1961; Folder 25A:16
    - newspaper [The Mentor] Massachusetts Correctional Institution, 1961-1962; Folder 25A:17
    - notes, 1961; undated; Folder 25A:18
    - obituary [John Bradshaw], 1962; Folder 25A:19
  - Box 25B
    - charters [Association of National Investigators; Association for Research and Enlightenment], 1927; 1931; Folder 25B:1
    - correspondence, 1966-1986; Folder 25B:2-25B:3
    - correspondence [A.R.E. Board of Trustees], 1945; 1977; Folder 25B:4
    - correspondence [Library of Congress Copyright Office], 1975; Folder 25B:5
    - correspondence [Chris and Henry Vaughn], 1972-1985; Folder 25B:6
    - extracts [Edgar Cayce Prayer Group readings, undated; Folder 25B:7
    - family tree [John Davis], 2009; Folder 25B:8
    - lectures and publications [Robert Adriance], 1965; Folder 25B:9
    - lectures and publications [Peter Ballbusch], 1966; Folder 25B:10
    - lectures and publications [Morton Blumenthal], 1928-1929; Folder 25B:11
    - lectures and publications [Franklin F. Bradley], 1929; Folder 25B:12
    - lectures and publications [Harmon Bro], 1943-1950; Folder 25B:13
    - lectures and publications [Thomas B. Brown], 1929; Folder 25B:14
    - lectures and publications [Edgar Evans Cayce], 1943-1964; Folder 25B:15
    - lectures and publications [Hugh Lynn Cayce], 1940-1954; Folder 25B:16
    - lectures and publications [Gina Cerminara], 1945-1984; Folder 25B:17
    - lectures and publications [Nell Clairmonte], 1969; Folder 25B:18
    - lectures and publications [Ralph Courtney], 1941; Folder 25B:19
    - lectures and publications [Florence Edmonds], 1932-1949; Folder 25B:20
    - lectures and publications [A.J. Foerter], 1932-1933; Folder 25B:21
    - lectures and publications [Lydia Schrader Gray], 1957; Folder 25B:22
    - lectures and publications [Henry Hardwicke], 1936-1939; Folder 25B:23
    - lectures and publications [Mrs. H.B. Harrell], 1933; Folder 25B:24
    - lectures and publications [Evelyn Millicent Horton], 1939; Folder 25B:25
    - lectures and publications [Virginia Learned], undated; Folder 25B:26
    - lectures and publications [Noah Miller], 1940-1973; Folder 25B:27
    - lectures and publications [Shane Miller], 1953-1961; Folder 25B:28
    - lectures and publications [Jennie Moore], 1949; Folder 25B:29
    - lectures and publications [Frances Y. Morrow], 1933-1937; Folder 25B:30
    - lectures and publications [John J. O'Neill], 1939; Folder 25B:31
    - lectures and publications [Laurie Pratt], 1933; Folder 25B:32
    - lectures and publications [Harold J. Reilly], 1947-1966; Folder 25B:33
    - lectures and publications [M.L. Richardson], 1933; Folder 25B:34
    - lectures and publications [Lytle Robinson], 1979; Folder 25B:35
    - lectures and publications [Gray Salter], 1933; Folder 25B:36
    - lectures and publications [Elsie Sechrist], 1956; Folder 25B:37
    - lectures and publications [Enid Severy Smith], undated; Folder 25B:38
    - lectures and publications [Mae Gimbert St. Clair], 1956; Folder 25B:39
    - lectures and publications [Thomas Sugrue], 1929-1952; Folder 25B:40
    - lectures and publications [Hazel Tops], 1979; Folder 25B:41
    - lectures and publications [Albert Turner], 1958-1968; Folder 25B:42
    - lectures and publications [Gladys Davis Turner], 1933-1981; Folder 25B:43-25B:44
    - lectures and publications [Marion Wolfe], 1941; Folder 25B:45
    - list [money refunded for appointments canceled], 1945; Folder 25B:46
    - magazine [Chimes Psychic Monthly], 1949-1950; Folder 25B:47
    - manuscript [The Book of Exodus] Eva Ringrose, 1972; Folder 25B:48
    - newsclippings, 1983-1986; Folder 25B:49
    - programs [Washington and Lee University commencement], 1930; Folder 25B:50
    - rosters [Gladys Davis Turner's Weekly Meeting with A.R.E. Conferees], 1977; Folder 25B:51
    - will [Gladys Davis Turner], 1973; Folder 25B:52
  - Box 25C
    - binder [Group A Dreams; Dream Readings Project], 1955-1956; Folder 25C:1
    - binder [Dream Readings Project extracts], 1955-1956; Folder 25C:2-25C:3
    - reindexing corrections and additions, 1980-1983; Folder 25C:4
    - correspondence [Dream Project], 1955-1956; Folder 25C:5
  - Box 25D
    - lecture notes [Dream Project participants], 1947-1949; Folder 25D:1
    - reports on dream experiences [Dream Project], 1951-1956; Folder 25D:2
    - work files, 1980-1985; Folder 25D:3-25D:6
- Books and oversize, 1909-1983
  - Box 26
    - book [American Osteopathic Association Yearbook and Directory of Osteopathic Physicians], 1981; Item 26:1
    - book [A Book of Friendship: Celebrating the Joys of Having Friends], 1977-1983; Item 26:2
    - book [Edgar Cayce's Photographic Legacy], 1978; Item 26:3
    - book [American Library Association Rules for Filing Catalog Cards], 1943; Item 26:4
    - book [The Magical Message According to Ioannes (St. John the Divine)], 1909; Item 26:5
    - book [The Nag Hammadi Library], 1977; Item 26:6
    - guest book [Gladys' 60th Anniversary celebration], 1983; Item 26:7
  - Box 27
    - book [The Management of Archives], 1965-1966; Folder 27:1-27:2
    - book [Modern Archives: Principles and Techniques], 1971; Folder 27:3
  - Box 28
    - print [Broad Street Looking North Circa 1890], undated; Item 28:1
    - diploma [Central City Business College], 1920; Item 28:2
    - poster [Be Thankful for Gladys Day Proclamation], 1971; Item 28:3